[dramatic music playing]
[grunts]
[Menthuthuyoupi] Wait a second.
I saw him on the stairs before.
Did he do it?
[Killua] Sorry, but I'm
a little pissed off right now,
so I'm just gonna
take it all out on you.
-[tense music playing]
-[electricity crackling]
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
STRONG X OR X WEAK
[electricity crackling, humming]
[Menthuthuyoupi] Huh? He's gone!
[electricity crackling]
[screaming]
[groans]
[growls]
[tense music playing]
[Killua] Godspeed.
[narrator] With no time whatsoever
to roar or transform,
Killua easily incapacitated Youpi.
Such was the disparity in initiative.
Killua's Godspeed
electrified his entire body,
allowing him to reach speeds
so high that they transcended
even the broadest limits
of his physical potential.
As it turned out,
Killua had divided this power
into two core functions.
The first was called
Speed of Lightning
and gave him control
at superhuman speed.
The second let him respond
automatically to his opponent
and was called Whirlwind.
In a previous fight,
he'd used the latter
to stop his opponent's
fish dart in its tracks.
It was a preprogrammed response
to what was clearly malevolent intent
in his enemy's aura.
A reflex
that actually served to bypass
the comparatively slow human brain,
it proved more than sufficient
in surpassing
the enemy's physical speed.
[Menthuthuyoupi]
What in the hell is going on here?
These attacks,
in terms of sheer power,
they're all less than a tenth
of my own strength.
This doesn't make any sense.
I can't do a thing against him.
[Killua] Whirlwind.
[Menthuthuyoupi] Unreal.
This aura stuff is really intense.
[chuckles]
This is getting kinda interesting.
Before my explosion,
I never would have enjoyed
fighting an uphill battle.
[narrator] This change in attitude
would lead Youpi to a surprising choice.
However, this would
not happen until later.
[Menthuthuyoupi chuckles]
[electricity crackling stops]
[gasps]
[Killua] Oops.
Damn. I used it up already.
Hold it!
You're never getting away
from me, you brat!
You and I are gonna
see this through to the end,
when you die!
Huh?
He disappeared? Again?
That little jerk just vanished
like he never existed.
That's it.
At least one of them
must have the ability
to appear and disappear at will.
It's the only way at all
that any of this makes sense!
[dramatic music playing]
[Bloster] Huh?
[automated voice]
Please enter your code number.
Aw, damn it.
I don't have a code number.
Um…
[beeps]
[automated voice] Your code and data
do not match.
Please reenter your code number.
A second input error will result
in your immediate restraint.
[Ikalgo] Don't tell me.
Did he really come down here
without knowing
about the code system?
Okay, that didn't work.
Guess I'll just have to get out.
[beeps]
[automated voice]
The door has been locked.
Please enter your code number.
[Ikalgo] This is it.
I have two options.
The elevator will eventually fill
with sleeping gas.
Once he's asleep,
I'll have to decide.
One, I just leave Bloster there
in the elevator,
and then I head for the surface
using the freight entrance.
MONITOR ROOM
That way, when he wakes up,
he'll still be stuck in the elevator.
But there's a high risk
that someone upstairs
will notice something's wrong.
Two, I move Bloster
somewhere else
while he's knocked out.
There are plenty
of parked cars around,
and the warehouse doors
need a code to open them
from the inside.
He won't be able to open them
when he wakes up.
Plus, I want to avoid
running into anyone if I can.
If I go upstairs
using the freight elevator,
there's much less
of a chance that'll happen.
No! That'll never work.
I have to kill Bloster
while he's asleep.
That's the safest way.
Then I'll have to take control
of Bloster's corpse
and use it to take out
the other Squadron Leaders.
It's the least I could do.
I'll stick the barrel of my gun
through the gap in his armor,
and then I'll open fire!
[narrator] Although Ikalgo's ability
allowed him to control corpses,
he had never actually
killed anyone before.
[automated voice]
Enter your code number immediately.
If an authorized code number
is not entered
within the next 30 seconds,
you will be taken into custody.
[grumbles]
[Ikalgo] The surveillance room
in the guard station.
There should be a feed
from the security camera
in the elevator
and a control to open the doors.
[keypad beeping]
-[gasps]
-[automatic gunfire]
[Bloster grunts]
Well, I'm out, but it's too bad
I had to completely
destroy the elevator
so I could get free.
Now, are there any other exits?
[tense music playing]
[Ikalgo] I was naive.
I didn't think
he'd shoot up the door.
What now? Do I wait for him
to lower his guard,
then sneak out
the freight entrance?
Or should I be patient
and wait for him to leave?
Either way,
if he goes back upstairs…
[grunting]
No! That's not good enough.
That's weak.
But if he goes back up to the surface
and tells the others that Flutter's dead,
I'll be able to move around
without fear.
Idiot!
If I let an enemy return to the surface,
the danger increases for everyone.
I can't.
Huh?
[groans]
[grunts]
[grumbles]
Man, that one is pretty thick.
[tense music playing]
Huh?
[grumbles]
[Ikalgo] I can't let him
go back upstairs.
If I can't stop him,
I have no right to be here.
[Bloster grumbles]
[Ikalgo] Come on. Come on.
Right into my trap.
Almost there.
Wait till he's a little farther from it.
[dramatic music playing]
[gasps]
[Ikalgo] Now!
Agh!
[Bloster] So there really
was someone besides Flutter.
If I didn't know better,
I'd think you were trying
to lure me in there.
-[Ikalgo groans]
-[Bloster chuckles]
Too bad for you.
If only one path remains,
it's just too good to be true.
Anyone would be suspicious.
Well, now I know you exist,
so that's something.
[laughs]
And I bet you're hiding
in the surveillance room
to observe me, you chicken!
[Ikalgo] Damn it. I was so close
to having him completely
trapped in that corridor,
but there's no way out
from where he is now.
He's still trapped.
Sleeping gas
will fill the room eventually,
and when it does…
[gasps] No! He isn't trapped!
There's still a way out!
[Bloster] I should probably
get out of here.
I'm willing to bet
that's sleeping gas.
[Ikalgo] I have to do something
before he figures it out.
Wait. The armored vehicles
in the garage.
With those,
I could at least lock him in,
but then I'll have no way
to get back upstairs.
Think. Is there anything here I can use?
I've gotta think of a plan, fast!
[Bloster] Looks like I'm gonna have
to blow through this bulkhead.
Man, this is really getting
to be a pain in the rear.
[Ikalgo] I've gotta do it!
[gunfire]
[Bloster] Damn. All that,
and I barely scorched the surface?
I guess I'm just gonna have
to come up
with something else then.
I know!
The bulkhead controls
are in the monitor room,
so I can go over there
to open the bulkheads.
Now we're talkin'.
Wait. I have to go
through a bulkhead
to reach the monitor room.
Damn it all.
Looks like I'm still
gonna have to destroy this one
if I want any chance
of getting back upstairs.
Hang on.
I wonder.
There might be a way to escape
without busting down a bulkhead.
Huh?
It's opening?
Is that a tank? [scoffs]
That's exactly the kind of thing
a gutless chicken would use.
But the bulkhead behind it's still shut,
and the door to the monitor room
is just beyond it.
Okay, that can only mean one thing.
First, he closed the front bulkhead,
and then he parked the vehicle there.
Then he returned to the monitor room
and started raising the front bulkhead
and lowering the back one.
Once he did,
he raced back to the vehicle.
Doesn't that mean
that he's trapped, too?
He blocked off his only escape route
just to force a showdown?
Hah! You're kidding.
Seriously? Come on.
[laughs]
So I guess there must be
someone else around here,
and they must be sitting up
in the control room watching me.
How dare they?
Well, watch this, you peeping Tom,
because I'm about to drag
your little buddy
out of this tank
and rip him to shreds!
[Ikalgo] I'm the only one here,
and I'm gonna have
to take care of this.
Man, that armor's tough.
[Bloster gasps]
[grunts]
[gulps]
[Ikalgo] I did it.
Ah, damn it.
The bastard blocked the elevator.
If he hadn't done that,
I could have blown a hole
in the ceiling
and climbed up the cable.
[tense music playing]
[Ikalgo] I've blocked his escape route.
First hurdle cleared.
Hmm? Man, you've got a lot of nerve,
you know that, buddy?
I'm gonna pump you full of bullets.
Hmm?
Smoke, huh?
So, is he dead?
Did he already lose?
Either way, there's no way
to move this thing.
The gap's only a few centimeters.
The entrance is completely blocked.
[roars]
[groans]
Now, come out!
Your friend is gonna burn to death!
If you act now,
I'm willing to spare you!
Open the damned bulkhead!
You hear me?
[Ikalgo] Being an octopus,
I only need a few centimeters
to squeeze through.
Second hurdle cleared.
[Bloster] Hey!
Open the bulkhead!
[coughing]
[Ikalgo] Now I just have to wait
for the sleeping gas to fill the room.
[Bloster coughing]
[groaning, coughing]
[Ikalgo] I can hold my breath,
but I don't want to waste
any more time.
I've gotta wait for the right moment.
[Bloster coughing]
[thud]
[grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[Ikalgo] Third hurdle cleared.
Don't rush.
Nice and slow.
This is the final hurdle.
[gags]
Just pull the trigger, and I'm done.
[heart beating]
[grunting]
This is the best option.
If I can take control of his corpse,
it'll be a lot safer upstairs,
so I've gotta do this!
There's… There's nobody else here.
There's no one else to help me!
I have to do this!
I have to!
[gagging]
[sobbing]
There's no way. I can't do it…
because I'm a coward!
[sobbing]
[narrator] Meanwhile, as Ikalgo
was lamenting his weakness,
Morel was within
the shifted central tower
facing off against Pouf's pupa,
but in addition to the physical fight
that would soon begin,
Morel was battling
serious doubts of his own.
[Morel] Hold on. What if…
[Menthuthuyoupi] Pitou, Pouf,
are you there? Answer me!
[Morel] What if no one
responded to Youpi's call
not because they chose to,
but because they weren't able to?
The pupa should just be
a goopy mess right now,
not a fully-formed creature.
If he's utterly defenseless
while he changes forms,
this is the best chance
I'm gonna get.
Time to attack!
He made a mistake,
a fatal one.
How could he have done that
in this situation?
It's not possible.
This has to be a trap.
There's no doubt in my mind.
The only question now
is whether it's a trap
that's already been activated
without me doing
anything to trigger it,
or whether it'll be activated
as soon as I attack.
Which is it?
[Shaiapouf]
You are having these doubts,
because you are exceptional.
However, that's all there is to it.
[closing theme music playing]
[Morel] So should I attack or not?
What do I do?
[singer singing in Japanese]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, "Fake and Real."
Hey, if not now, then when?
[Killua] No! Not yet, fool!
[Gon] You're not Killua. You're a fake.
[singer singing in Japanese]